<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alwin Arrasyid</title>
    <link>https://alwint3r.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Alwin Arrasyid</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 19:43:13 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alwint3r.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of mongo-datatable</title>
      <link>https://alwint3r.github.io/posts/the-state-of-mongo-datatable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 19:43:13 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alwint3r.github.io/posts/the-state-of-mongo-datatable/</guid>
      <description>I have published several open source libraries in my career as software engineer. Most of them are not popular and not widely used judging from some statistics. You can find them on my github profile and on organizations that I&amp;rsquo;m a part of. Anyway I&amp;rsquo;m gonna talk about the module that I published for the first time ever, that is mongo-datatable. It is a node.js module for dealing with server-side processing for jQuery datatables using MongoDB as the database engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sending Firmware Version Over LoRa</title>
      <link>https://alwint3r.github.io/posts/sending-firmware-version-over-lora/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 21:17:55 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alwint3r.github.io/posts/sending-firmware-version-over-lora/</guid>
      <description>There was a case where We need to keep the server informed about the version of firmware that is running on our devices. The devices are not directly connected to the internet, instead they send data through LoRa hence sending the version information can be a little tricky.
We used LoRaWAN instead of LoRa PTP because it is well-defined protocol by LoRa Alliance and is easy to set up on both the edge and the cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://alwint3r.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 19:04:48 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alwint3r.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Alwin Arrasyid is a software engineer, public speaker and trainer around internet of things topic, also an enthusiast of technology in general. Alwin has spoken in various IoT-related events such as Road to Republic of IoT, Republic of IoT, Republic of IoT Strikes Back! and another big events such as Global Azure Bootcamp, Python Conference ID 2017 at Surabaya representing DycodeX as the gold sponsor of the event. Alwin is currently working as Lead Software Engineer at DycodeX, an IoT solutions and maker movement enabler company.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>